The Peoples of the Pirá-Paraná Collection of Stephen Hugh-Jones and Christine Hugh-Jones
Nettie Lee Benson Latin American Collection,
The Peoples of the Pirá-Paraná Collection of Stephen Hugh-Jones and Christine Hugh-Jones
1968-1996
Hugh-Jones, Stephen; Hugh-Jones, Mary Christine
2021-30
3 linear feet
Benson Latin American Collection, The University of Texas at Austin
This collection consists of audiocassette and open reel audiotape recordings of the Tukanoan-speaking people of Southeastern Colombia.
Historical Note
Stephen and Christine Hugh-Jones were social anthropologists and published authors of many works concerning history, ethnicity, and the Amazon Forest. Stephen and Christine’s first trip to the Amazon was in 1968, and most recently in 2017. The couple were dedicated to their research, and went to great lengths to incorporate themselves into the culture when conducting participant observation in the field. Stephen and Christine continued to visit the Amazon and the Pirá-Paraná People after their PhD studies, and in 1979 even brought their two children with them. In 1980 Christine began to pursue a medical degree while Stephen continued his work as a social anthropologist with a focus on Amazonia. Both Stephen and Christine have consulted on documentary films on the peoples of the Amazon such as War of the Gods and Ignacio’s Legacy. Stephen is now a Life Fellow at King’s College in Cambridge and Christine is a medical doctor for the unhoused population.
This archival collection contains audio recordings relating to the languages, culture, society and history of the Tukanoan-speaking Barasana, Bará, Eduria, Itana, Karapana, Makuna and Tatuyo peoples living in and around the basin of the Río Pirá Paraná in the Departamento del Vaupés in Southeastern Colombia.
The archival collection is the outcome of the Hugh-Jones’ repeated visits to the Pirá Paraná region from 1968 to 2017 for anthropological and linguistic research, for work relating to culturally-appropriate education in collaboration with the Asociación de Capitanes y Autoridades Tradicionales Indígenas del Río Pirá Paraná (ACAIPI) and for film-making in collaboration with Brian Moser, Howard Reid and Wade Davis. Funding for these visits was provided by the Social Science Research Council, the Economic and Social Research Council, King’s College, Cambridge, the Firebird Foundation, the British Museum, La Fundación Gaia-Amazonas, UNESCO, Granada Television and Central Television.
Scope and Contents Note
The Peoples of the Pirá-Paraná Collection of Stephen Hugh-Jones and Christine Hugh-Jones is divided into two series: Audiocassette Tapes and Open Reel Audiotapes. The first series, audiocassettes, is divided into eight subseries. Those subseries are: Reunión San Miguel ACAIPI, Barasana Tapes, Unmarked tape circa 1980, Desana - Rio Papuri (Brasil), Colombia 1991, Recoya Hido, Message Hilda -> Mother 08.96; Ika~ra keti, and Umero Myths. The open reel audiotapes are also divided into eight subseries. Those subseries are: Myth, Description, Conversation, Music, Ritual, Commentary, Chant, and Miscellaneous. It is important to note that a single open reel audiotape can fall into multiple subseries due to the various recordings on a single tape.
Boxes 1, 2, and 3 are stored in Library Storage Facility container A. Boxes 4 and 5 are stored in Library Storage Facility container B. Boxes 6 and 7 are stored in Library Storage Facility container C.
Hyperlinks to the digitized AILLA files are provided within the finding aid.
Access Restrictions
This collection is stored remotely. Advance notice is required for retrieval. Please contact bensonspecialcollections@austin.utexas.edu
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Hugh-Jones, Stephen; Hugh-Jones, Mary Christine
Subject (Organizations)
Archive of Indigenous Languages of Latin America
Subjects
Indigenous peoples--Languages; Indigenous education
Places
Brazil; Colombia
Document Types
audiocassettes; open reel audiotapes
Related Material
Archive of Indigenous Languages of Latin America (AILLA) Collection
Hugh-Jones Notebooks 1968-1970, AILLA Database
Hugh-Jones Notebooks 1979, AILLA Database
Hugh-Jones Notebooks 1981-2016, AILLA Database
Hugh-Jones Ethnoeducation Photographs, AILLA Database
Acquisition Information
Donation.
Additions
No further materials are expected for this collection.
Box and Folder Inventory
- Audiocassette Tapes
  - Reunion San Miguel ACAIPI, Gaia, Min de Educn., 1996 August 16-1996 August 24
    Housed in LSF container A
    - [SHJ-001] Reunion Educación San Miguel 1 (Box 1, Item 1)
    - [SHJ-002] Reunion Educación San Miguel 2 (Box 1, Item 2)
    - [SHJ-003-A.mp3] Reunion Educación San Miguel 3 (Box 1, Item 3)
    - [SHJ-004] Reunion Educación San Miguel 4 (Box 1, Item 4)
    - [SHJ-005] Reunion Educación San Miguel 5 (Box 1, Item 5)
    - [SHJ-006] Reunion Educación San Miguel 6 (Box 1, Item 6)
    - [SHJ-007] Reunion Educación San Miguel 7 (Box 1, Item 7)
    - [SHJ-008] Reunion Educación San Miguel 8 (Box 1, Item 8)
    - [SHJ-009] Reunion Educación San Miguel 10 (Box 1, Item 9)
    - [SHJ-010-A.mp3] Reunion Educación San Miguel 11 (Box 1, Item 10)
    - [SHJ-011] Reunion Educación San Miguel 12 (Box 1, Item 11)
    - [SHJ-012] Reunion Educación San Miguel 13 (Box 1, Item 12)
    - [SHJ-013] Reunion Educación San Miguel 14 (Box 1, Item 13)
    - [SHJ-014] Reunion Educación San Miguel 15 (Box 1, Item 14)
    - [SHJ-015] Reunion Educación San Miguel 16 (Box 1, Item 15)
    - [SHJ-016] Reunion Educación San Miguel 17 (Box 1, Item 16)
    - [SHJ-017] Reunion Educación San Miguel 18 (Box 1, Item 17)
    - [SHJ-018] Reunion Educación San Miguel 19 (Box 1, Item 18)
    - [SHJ-019] Reunion Educación San Miguel 20 (Box 1, Item 19)
    - [SHJ-020] Reunion Educación San Miguel 21 (Box 1, Item 20)
    - [SHJ-022] Reunion Educación San Miguel 22 (Box 1, Item 21)
    - [SHJ-022] Reunion Educación San Miguel 22 (Box 1, Item 22)
    - [SHJ-023] Reunion Educación San Miguel 23 (Box 1, Item 23)
    - [SHJ-024] Reunion Educación San Miguel 23 (Box 1, Item 24)
    - [SHJ-026] Reunion Educación San Miguel 24 (Box 1, Item 25)
    - [SHJ-026] Reunion Educación San Miguel 24 (Box 1, Item 26)
    - [SHJ-027] Reunion Educación San Miguel 25 (Box 1, Item 27)
    - [SHJ-028] Reunion Educación San Miguel 25 (Box 1, Item 28)
    - [SHJ-029] Reunion Educación San Miguel 26 (Box 1, Item 29)
    - [SHJ-030] Reunion Educación San Miguel 27 (Box 1, Item 30)
    - [SHJ-031] Reunion Educación San Miguel 28 (Box 1, Item 31)
    - [SHJ-032] Reunion Educación San Miguel 29 (Box 1, Item 32)
    - [SHJ-033] Reunion Educación San Miguel 30 (Box 1, Item 33)
    - [SHJ-034] Reunion Educación San Miguel 31 (Box 1, Item 34)
    - [SHJ-035] Reunion Educación San Miguel 32 (Box 1, Item 35)
    - [SHJ-036] Reunion Educación San Miguel 33 (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Barasana Tapes
    - [SHJ-037] Ewa yai büho keti (Power Jaguar and Thunder story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 37)
    - [SHJ-037] ~Uba ~wati keti (Uma spirit story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 37)
    - [SHJ-037] Ayawa oko ~bakar~ra okowü keti (Ayawa seek water story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 37)
    - [SHJ-037] ~Wati Biru keti (Biru Spirit story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 37)
    - [SHJ-038] ~Wati Biru keti gaha (Biru Spirit story contd.), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 38)
    - [SHJ-038] ~Wati Biru keti gaha (Biru Spirit story contd.), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 38)
    - [SHJ-038] Kawayaria keti (about the Kawayaria, Bará clan), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 38)
    - [SHJ-038] Yeba, koaro~ba keti (Yeba and gourd vine story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 38)
    - [SHJ-038] Kawia keti (crab story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 38)
    - [SHJ-038] ~Wati Bokü keti (White Spirit story start), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 38)
    - [SHJ-038] ~Yaba ~suagü, ~yaba ~kahuro keti (Deer and Dance story start), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 38)
    - [SHJ-039] ~Wati Bokü Keti gaha (White Spirit story end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-039] ~Yaba ~suagü, ~yaba ~kahuro keti gaha (Deer and Dance story end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-039] Hee ~basa hoe~hea wadise (Coming of first people), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-039] ~Yukabadahiro keti (Bagworm story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-039] Bükü~ra Yaia, Yesea keti (Jaguar and peccaries story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - [SHJ-039] ~Opeo ~Wati keti (Breast-spirit story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-039] ~Güta yaiya (on fossils), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-039] Yokeri ~Basa (Sinister creatures), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-039] Eri Bühühogo keti (Bushmaster and owl story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-039] ~Wati güde ~bagü keti (Spirit with no Anus story start), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - [SHJ-040] ~Wati güde ~bagü keti gaha (Spirit with no Anus story end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - [SHJ-040] ~Watiare biaraka bue~ra keti (spirits killed by chilli smoke story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - [SHJ-040] Wahü keti (Wahü story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - [SHJ-040] Hee gahe~udi goti~ra (About ritual posessions), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - [SHJ-040] Yeba, bühü, waso boti keti (Yeba, Spider and bark aprons), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - [SHJ-040] Wai ~Hido Yeba keti (Fish anaconda and Yeba story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - [SHJ-040]~Kii Rükü ~Hido keti (Manioc-stick anaconda story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - [SHJ-040] ~Robi ~Kubu Hee huarudise keti (Romi Kumu steals Yurupary story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - [SHJ-041] ~Kii Rükü ~Hido keti gaha (Manioc-stick anaconda story end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 41)
    - [SHJ-041] ~Waribi keti (Warimi story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 41)
    - [SHJ-041] ~Waribi keti gaha (Warimi story end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 41)
    - [SHJ-042] ~Robi ~Kubu hee ~basa hoe~hea wadise (Romi Kumu and coming of ancestors), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 42)
    - [SHJ-042] Süa~ra ewura hü keti (Sticky leach-people at Ewura story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 42)
    - [SHJ-042] Kahea ~wagero ~wati (Eye-eating spirit), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - [SHJ-042] ~Waribi, ~Aya hako keti (Warimi and Snake Mother story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 42)
    - [SHJ-042] ~Waribi, ~Rabe ~Riba ~Hido keti (Warimi, Rame and Posion Anaconda), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 42)
    - [SHJ-043] ~Waribi, ~Rabe ~Riba ~Hido keti gaha (Warimi, Rame and Posion Anaconda end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 43)
    - [SHJ-043] ~Uyu ~Yokoroa keti (Unyu nyokoroa story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 43)
    - [SHJ-043] ~Basü, gaa keti (Man and eagle story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 43)
    - [SHJ-043] ~Basü, yai keti (story of man and jaguar), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 43)
    - [SHJ-044] ~Basü, yai keti gaha (story of man and jaguar end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - [SHJ-044] ^Aya wese keti (Snakes and chagras), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - [SHJ-044] Werea, berua keti (On Bees), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - [SHJ-044] ~Kii Rükü ~Hido keti (Manioc-stick anaconda story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - [SHJ-044] ~Robia ~ida ~bakü kütise (On childbirth), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - [SHJ-044] Bara keti (Love magic), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - [SHJ-044] Barasana sites, 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - [SHJ-044] Bohori ~watia keti (On masked mourning rituals), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - [SHJ-045] Bohori ~watia keti gaha (on masked mourning rituals end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 45)
    - [SHJ-045] ~Kobeyahü waküdise (Description of voyage to Komenya), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 45)
    - [SHJ-045] ~Yagore kütise (Chanting for us - too fast), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 45)
    - [SHJ-045] Yeba keti (Yeba story) Contd T10, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 45)
    - [SHJ-046] Yeba keti gaha (Yeba story end), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] ~Buhi hakü keti (Owner of roofing leaves story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] Wese ~boare gotise (On garden work), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] ~Uba ~Wati keti gaha Uma Wati story (end), 1969 May 25-1969 May 26 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] Kahi ekaria ~yagose (formal speech for giving coca), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] ~Baka ~yabo keti (Maka nyamo story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] ~Waribi keti (Warimi story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] Yeba keti (Yeba story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] ~Wati Bokü keti (White spirit story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] ~Wati güde ~bagü keti (Spirit with no Anus story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-046] Guu, Yai keti (Tortoise and jaguar story), 1970 February 13 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - [SHJ-047] Guu, Yai keti gaha (Tortoise and jaguar story end), 1970 February 13 (Box 2, Item 47)
    - [SHJ-047] ~Yokoago keti (Falling star story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 47)
    - [SHJ-047] Guu ~kihika keti (Small tortoise story), 1970 February 13 (Box 2, Item 47)
    - [SHJ-047] ~Kii Rükü ~Hido keti (Manioc stick Anaconda story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 47)
    - [SHJ-047] ~Waribi ~Aya hako keti (Warimi and Snake mother story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 47)
    - [SHJ-047] Busuri ~yoko keti gaha (Morning star end), 1969 May 24 (Box 2, Item 47)
    - [SHJ-047] ~Uba ~Wati keti (Uma spirit story), 1969 May 25-1969 May 26 (Box 2, Item 47)
    - [SHJ-048] ~Uba ~Wati keti (Uma spirit story end), 1969 May 25-1969 May 26 (Box 2, Item 48)
    - [SHJ-048] Yeba, ~wabü, wekü keti (Yeba, umarí and tapir story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 48)
    - [SHJ-048] ~Waribi keti gotise (Warimi story - explanation), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 48)
    - [SHJ-048] Yeba keti (Yeba story), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 48)
    - [SHJ-049] Yeba keti gaha (Yeba story end), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] Basere (Shamanic spells), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] Villavo keti (Desc. of Villavicencio), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] ~Badahü, ~badaho kütise (Marriage morals), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] ~Basa tuburi (On groups), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] ~Übüagü ~yabiagü keti (Sun and Moon change roles), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] Hee wii bedise (Post-initiation restrictions), 1970 August 7 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] ~Waribi keti (Warimi story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] Hea güso keti (Fire cayman - origin of fire story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] Ajawa keti (Ayawa story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] ~Robi ~Kubu hee hua rudise keti (Romi Kumu steals Yurupary story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] Kii rükü ~hido ~Beka ~bidi keti (Manioc stick anaconda and ant bird story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-049] Pacho rodori keti (Account of season acc. Pacho), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - [SHJ-050] Warībi keti (Warimi story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] Hea güso keti (Fire cayman - origin of fire story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] Ayawa keti (Ayawa story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~kii rükü ~hido ~beka ~bidi keti (Manioc stick anaconda and ant bird story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] Pacho rodori keti (Account of season acc. Pacho), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Kode keti (woodpecker story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Wati keti (Spirit story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Uba ~wati (Uma spirit story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Buhihu ~robiare wüagü, ~goa baagü keti (Moon's copulation w. women), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Buhihu ~goa baagü keti (Moon eats bones), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Basa ~ida ruhease keti (Creation of People story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Heyerio küti~ra (ritual friendship at initiation), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Badahü, ~badaho kütise (on Marriage), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] ~Gaseroabü, ~goha keti (cockroach and ~goha frog story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-050] Yeba keti (Yeba story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-051] ~I hakü keti (On his father etc), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - [SHJ-051] ~Yagose (talk), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-051] Baare bedise (Food taboos), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-051] Maha keti (on macaws), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-051] Maximiliano ~raka ~yagogü (Talk w. Maximiliano), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-051] Wii hakü keti (House, roofing-leaf father story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-051] Baare ekaria wii, hee wii gotiro (Descr. of food exchange and initiation), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-051] ~Robi ~Kubu gataro keti (~Robi ~Kubu makes manioc griddle), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-051] ~Wati, ~Ebü keti (Spirit and morpho butterfly story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-051] ~Wati keti (Spirit story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - [SHJ-052] ~Wati keti gaha (Spirit story end), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] ~Robi ~kubu übuari ruheago keti (Romi Kumu creates the world), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] ~Yago-~hedira (Chat), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] Hee; ~yago-~hedira (Yurupary, chat), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] üko ~hido keti (Medicine Anaconda story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] Guu ~kihika keti (small tortoise story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] ~Yokoago keti (Falling Star story), 1970 March 21 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] ~Gohao keti (Frog-woman story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] ~Dikorete ~bosiro keti (Toad and cricket story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-052] Buo keti (Agouti woman story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - [SHJ-053] Buo keti gaha (Agouti woman story end), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 53)
    - [SHJ-053] ~Waribi keti (Warimi story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 53)
    - [SHJ-053] Ayawaroa, ~Waribi, Riba ~Hido keti (Ayawa, Warimi, Poison Anaconda story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 53)
    - [SHJ-053] ~Waribi Riba ~Hido keti (Warimi Poison Anaconda story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 53)
    - [SHJ-054] ~Waribi Riba ~Hido keti (Warimi Poison Anaconda story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 54)
    - [SHJ-054] Hee ~yo keti (Yurupary palm story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 54)
    - [SHJ-055-A] ~Waribi keti (Warimi story), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 55)
    - [SHJ-055-A] Wai bükü~ra ~waberi (animal names), 1968 (Box 2, Item 55)
    - [SHJ-056] War of the Gods soundtrack/Recordings, 1971 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] ~Iya ~Soora (caterpillar ritual) (only part of side A), 1968 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] Guu koro weewo ~raka (Syncopated tortoise after panppipe dance), 1968 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] Basase (Singing), 1970 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] Weewo basa (Panppipe dance), 1969 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] Weewo basa (Panpipe dance); ~weka~raka basa~ra (dance w. bamboo poles), 1968 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] ~Suhu (Snail-shell ocarina), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] Ariki Badya basase kesogü (sings Ariki baya's song fr Komenya), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] ~yago kütise ~sigüde (Chanting alone), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] ~Yago kütise (Chanting), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-056] Weewo basa, ~yago kütise, basase (Panpipe dance, chant, songs), 1968 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - [SHJ-057] ~Yago kütise (chanting at hee rika soria wii), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 57)
    - [SHJ-057] Hee, soori bükü (Yurupary trumpets + chatter), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 57)
    - [SHJ-057] Hee, yoese (Yurupary flutes), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 57)
    - [SHJ-057] Basa~ra ~yasa raka, hee rika sooria wiihü (Maraca dance at hee rika sooria wii), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 57)
    - [SHJ-057] ~Yagore kütise, hee, hee rika sooria wii, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 57)
    - [SHJ-057] Weewo basa (Panpipes), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 57)
    - [SHJ-058] Weewo basa (Panpipe dance, hee rika sooria wii), 1968 (Box 2, Item 58)
    - [SHJ-058] ~Yasa basa (Dance songs inc. ~yasa basa), 1968 (Box 2, Item 58)
    - [SHJ-058] Basagü (singing), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 58)
    - [SHJ-058] Baare ekaria wii: ~yagora, basa~ra (Chanting, dancing, bare ekaria wii), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 58)
    - [SHJ-058] Weewo basa, ~yagora (Panpipe dance, chant), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 58)
    - [SHJ-058] Basagü (singing dance songs), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 58)
    - [SHJ-059] ~Yasa basa (Maraca dance song), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] ~Yagogü (Chanting), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Rasea-ye basase weewo~raka (Tukano song, then drowned by panpipes), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] ~Yagogü (Chanting), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Basagü (singing), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] ~Yagogü (Chanting), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Basagü (singing), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Rasea-ye basase (Tukano song), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Basa (song), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] ~Yaba ~goa (Deer bone flute), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Weewo basa (Panpipes), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Basagü (song), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Hee (Yurupary instruments), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] Basa~ra (dance songs), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-059] üde ~watia basa (masked pupunha spirit dance songs), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - [SHJ-060-A] Basa~ra (songs), 1968 (Box 2, Item 60)
    - [SHJ-060-A] ~Iya soora (caterpillar ritual), 1968 (Box 2, Item 60)
  - Unmarked tape circa 1980
    - [SHJ-083-A] Gotigü (talk on Decline of customs), undated (Box 2, Item 83/M)
    - [SHJ-083-A] Rasea ~yago~ra (Tukano's talk), 1980s (Box 2, Item 83/M)
    - [SHJ-083-A] Canto Santa Cruz (Canto Santa Cruz millenarian movement songs), 1980s (Box 2, Item 83/M)
    - [SHJ-083-A] Süe basa, yago basa keti (Millenarian rituals; masked mourning rituals in past), 1979 (Box 2, Item 83/M)
    - [SHJ-083-A] Wai bükü~ra basere (Game animal shamanism), 1979 (Box 2, Item 83/M)
    - [SHJ-125] Copy tape (duplicate of Tape M), undated (Box 3, Item 125)
  - Desana - Rio Papuri (Brasil)
    - [SHJ-084] Waku baya ~kubu, undated (Box 2, Item 84)
    - [SHJ-084] (Canto) Santa Cruz, undated (Box 2, Item 84)
    - [SHJ-084] Beg. of ~pabüdi here, undated (Box 2, Item 84)
  - Colombia, 1991
    - [SHJ-085-A] Untitled (Box 2, Item 85)
    - [SHJ-085-B] Untitled (Box 2, Item 85)
    - [SHJ-086-A] Wesehü büsüse (garden sounds) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-A] Filmación goti~ra reunión-hü (meeting to explain filming) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-A] Wiihü büsüse (house sounds) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Filmación goti~ra reunión-hü (meeting to explain filming) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Filmación goti~ra reunión-hü (meeting to explain filming) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Oro ~boase keti (about working gold in Traíra) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Oro keti (about impact of gold, future etc) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Oro keti (about impact of gold, future etc) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Oko büsüse (rain sounds) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Busurihaü büsüse ~bakarokahü, bakahü (forest, village in early am sounds) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] ~Buhihu rihase basere (expl. of shamanism related to solar eclipse) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Büsüse makahü ~buhihu rihase hüdo (sounds outside house after solar eclipse) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-086-B] Kahi ~ suase büsüse (coca picking sounds~) (Box 2, Item 86)
    - [SHJ-087-A] Yeba kahi keti ketiaka (Yeba and coca - fragment) (Box 2, Item 87)
    - [SHJ-087-A] ~Yagogü Esteban-raka (talking w. SHJ) (Box 2, Item 87)